In the new movie The Internship, Vince
Vaughn and Owen Wilson play middle-aged
out of work salesman that somehow
land Google internships.
That's a sharpie by the way, genius.
That's my fault.
The movie focuses on a fierce
competition among the interns to
get full-time jobs at Google,
but in real life, the challenge
is just landing a Google internship.
It was immediately captivating.
New York native and Yale student,
Florian Collins Berger is an intern
for the marketing department.
This seemed like the smartest place
to pick up a lot of different skills
in one summer.
I've never been put in an environment
where work and play are so sort
of seamlessly integrated and still
felt productive.
He is one of the 1,500 interns
selected this summer out of a record
high pool of more than 40,000
applicants.
At that rate, it's harder to get
into the Google internship program
than into Harvard or Stanford.
Kyle Ewing heads the internship
program.
There's no best way to get into Google,
at the end of the day we're looking
for students who are smart,
who are creative, who are leaders,
who are passionate inside and outside
of work, who care about their community
and who really care about technology.
Applicants must be full-time students,
if they make it past the written
application phase, they go through
a series of phone and face-to-face
interviews with questions reportedly
ranging from coding to quirky.
In addition to the famous Google
perks like free food,
campus bikes and gym access,
interns also get paid a competitive
wage.
The average Google intern makes
about 5,800 dollars per month.
If you're a software engineer intern
at Google, you're making about
6,500 dollars per month,
even more and that's upwards of
75,000 dollars per year.
75,000 dollars per year is much
higher than the average U.S.
worker.
Interns are expected to complete
a project and get hands on experience.
Even in my first few weeks, I'd
put out code that everyone was
using and it was really cool to
call my mom and get to say like "Mom,
Mom look what I'm doing!"     Software
engineer Kitt Vanderwater, interned for
Google for two summers,
and is now a full-time employee.
As soon as I started my senior
year I knew I'd have a job at Google
and that was really great peace
of mind.
Something most interns are hoping
to get when they return for their
senior year.
In San Francisco, I'm Kara Tsuboi,
CNET.com for CBS News.