It's no surprise President Obama's
oldest daughter Malia will attend
Harvard University, the school
from which both her parents received
law degrees.
But what is raising some eyebrows
is the year off Malia will take,
a gap year as it's called,
before she begins Harvard in the
fall of 2017.
Can taking a year off before college
be beneficial to a student?
Elizabeth Armstrong is professor
of sociology and organizational
studies at the University of Michigan
and she joins us now.
Hi Elizabeth, thanks for being with us.
Hi, thanks for having me.
So, Elizabeth, do you see this
as being a positive for almost
any student?
I think so, I think that the additional
space to have some chance to grow
up and get some autonomy,
I think it's a good thing.
So clearly Malia Obama is in a
unique position but for other students
whose parents perhaps do not run
the country, does taking a year
off carry with it a stigma that
could be interpreted as being lazy?
I don't think so, I think the main
challenge is that obviously most
families don't have the resources
of the Obamas and the issue of
funding the gap year in a way that
makes it kind of developmentally
useful in some sense can be a
challenge.
But actually because for a lot
of young people simply getting
into the workforce a little bit
can be a good thing.
I have a question about that,
if you are going into the workforce
with that gap year, should you
do something that is career oriented
or do you just want to make some
money and save up for school?
Well, I think either because I
think in some ways one of the reasons
why a gap year can be very beneficial
is it's about sort of psychological
and emotional development,
to have the maturity to handle
the complexity of the college
environment, getting some space
from parents, getting some space
from everybody's expectations,
the expectations of your peers,
of teachers, of parents,
and really trying to figure out
who you are as a person and what
you want, and even just getting
some expertise with things like
a laundry maybe, you know,
balancing a checkbook,
things like that.
I can see how taking that breather
after the stress of senior year
can help sort of clear your mind
and let you enter college with
a renewed sort of purpose and energy,
but what are some of the specific
things that you recommend students
do with a gap year?
Community service, internships.
What are some of great ideas?
I was just talking with my son
who's taking a gap year this year,
he's taking a gap year after his
first year of college and his advice
was travel but don't do it with
any kind of program or travel agent,
just go.
Arrange it yourself,
buy the tickets yourself,
just really go out into the world
and do it on your own.
And then for that, I mean,
he's funded his year,
so I think that's part of it too.
It's because the necessity is
developing more autonomy.
I think that if the kids can kind
of have some kind of skin in the
game in the sense of working to
make the money for the traveling…
In your son's case, did he save
up before senior year?
Did he work to save up money for
the gap year?
Well, actually he took the first
year and then he spent the first
semester working landscaping just
around town to save up money.
Well, of course, that wouldn't
have worked if he wasn't sort of
still like living at home and kind
of being supported in a lot of
ways with me which comes back to
the privilege issue.
I mean, for this to really be something
that can be beneficial,
there is a certain amount of financial
aspects to it.
It may exacerbate inequalities
in some ways rather than level them.
So do we know how common the gap
year is among United States'
students?
I don't know if there's been any
systematic research on that yet.
I mean anecdotally, I think it's
becoming more common.
I know at least one of my son's
friends did it as well.
When I talk to people of my generation,
a number of them are like "oh yeah
I kind of did that but we didn't
really talk about it then."    We
didn't have a name for it,
now it's called the gap year.
There was just taking some time off.
I can totally see the benefits of it.
Thank you so much Elizabeth Armstrong
for all that.