You know there's always something
about that tangle of strangers
pressed together for days with
nothing in common but the need
to go from one place to another
and never see each other again.
I see evil on this train.
A passenger has died.
So they got him after all.
You assume he was killed?
No, no, no, no.
He was in perfectly good health,
he had his enemies.
Indeed, he was murdered.
Good God!
A murder?
Here?
(inaudible) Someone was rummaging
around my cabin in the middle of
the night, no one would listen to me.
If there was a murder,
What is going on?
…
then there was a murderer.
The murderer is with us,
and every one of you is a suspect.
And who are you?
My name is Hercule Poirot and I'm
probably the greatest detective
in the world.