You're looking particularly beautiful tonight
Ching
We have a problem
Good
The identities of our serving agents have been exposed
The country is in a state of complete chaos
and the universe sends me you...
Sir!
Yes alright Boff we're going on a mission not a honeymoon
Yes of course Sir...
Destination?
South of France, Sir
Arm the missiles...
They're just cyclists Sir...
They're French cyclists Boff
and they're obstructing Her Majesties Secret Service
She's the key to this case
I'm not sure I've ever met a man quite like you
Well let me clear up the uncertainty for you...
You haven't
Virtual reality?
It's completely immersive and some people loose track of their actual surroundings...
I think we can pretty much guarantee that that's not going to happen
Tell me the agent you've got in the field is making some progress...
Target acquired, this is a job for the shoebox inflate...
NO DON'T PULL IT IN THE CAR!
Can you reach your door handle?
Not, not really Sir...
Magnetic boots
Brilliant Sir
No one must have the slightest clue we're here...
*Alarm*
Till we meet again
That was sooner than I expected